[{"id": "5ffe4ab247818f5674af01ae", "question": "From which novel is this quote \"I am not afraid of storms, for I am learning how to sail my ship\u201d?", "answer": "\"Little Women\" (Amy March says this to Laurie about their marriage in the classic Louisa May Alcott novel.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a530", "question": "What city is located at the junction of the Allegheny River and Monongahela River?", "answer": "Pittsburgh", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9b8", "question": "The Province of Saskatchewan shares its southern border with which two US states?", "answer": "Montana and North Dakota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6a25720565ad31a57c7ab", "question": "Which brewery won the \"top beer award\" at Chicago's World Fair in 1893?", "answer": "Pabst Brewing Company", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c11", "question": "In what year was comedian Stephen Colbert born?", "answer": "1964", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c68e", "question": "What element\u2019s chemical symbol is \"Ni\"?", "answer": "Nickel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "592eadc3f83302ff91e46480", "question": "How is Alistair Leslie Graham better known as on TV?", "answer": "Ali G", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7ccff877e98cb97778a30", "question": "What shape is in the center of Switzerland's flag?", "answer": "Cross", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8f8b001dd7bf43be5e846", "question": "\"All the news that's fit to print\" is the motto of which newspaper?", "answer": "The New York Times", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a36e", "question": "What is the capital of Syria?", "answer": "Damascus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59bb2911c9bff04efae6d754", "question": "In what 1967 film did Gene Hackman earn his first Oscar nomination?", "answer": "Bonnie and Clyde", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b17466cbb2d29f81593b707", "question": "Which TV detective series is set in the town of Denton?", "answer": "A Touch of Frost", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dce", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"tungsten\"?", "answer": "Swedish", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c697", "question": "In the human body, what is produced by the Islets of Langerhans?", "answer": "Insulin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e1f1fe83fe1f2a824b9a", "question": "After changing sides during World War II, what was Italy's primary objective?", "answer": "It distracted Germany from accomplishing its main objectives", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a23c", "question": "Who released the album \"Madman Across the Water\" in 1971?", "answer": "Elton John\u00a0", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a8a", "question": "What cartoon duo gave us the \"Happy Happy Joy Joy\" song?", "answer": "Ren & Stimpy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015eee5fe83fe1f2a824c0a", "question": "What color of a cat is mainly associated with the commemoration of Halloween?", "answer": "A black cat is associated with Halloween. Legend has it that black cats were believed to be reincarnated witches.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394e7", "question": "Who played the judge in the TV show \"Night Court\"?", "answer": "Harry Anderson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399d2", "question": "Which ghost did Carol Kane portray in the 1988 film \"Scrooged\"?", "answer": "Ghost of Christmas Present", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b211", "question": "Who was assassinated by Gavrilo Princip?", "answer": "Archduke Ferdinand", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac58", "question": "What year did World War II end?", "answer": "1945", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be33", "question": "How many players are there in a standard American football team?", "answer": "Eleven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b632", "question": "In NATO's phonetic alphabet, what is the letter \"B\" referred to as?", "answer": "Bravo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389ec", "question": "What D.H. Lawrence novel with a colorful title was banned in the U.K. following a 1915 obscenity trial?", "answer": "The Rainbow", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e5f", "question": "Who provided the original voice for Shrek?", "answer": "Mike Myers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f4fdff048f679a45aacf", "question": "Mysophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Dirt and germs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b15e", "question": "What year was Mother Teresa born?", "answer": "1910", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c34f", "question": "What shape is the body of an Erlenmeyer flask?", "answer": "Conical", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea45c0ff048f679a45ab98", "question": "What digestive tract illness often is a manifestation of diabetes?", "answer": "Gastroparesis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339699", "question": "Which movie gave us the line \"You talkin' to me?\"", "answer": "Taxi Driver", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339809", "question": "What Norwegian pop band included Morten, Pal & Mags?", "answer": "A Ha", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338be3", "question": "During the 1st and 2nd centuries AD, which language was used to write the New Testament?", "answer": "Greek", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "595243c0736d4be723796b68", "question": "\"Blackstar\" was whose last album, released just days before his death?", "answer": "David Bowie's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cdc", "question": "What sci-fi movie featured Michael Rennie and Patricia Neal?", "answer": "The Day the Earth Stood Still", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefbee06ce05a3942286ef8", "question": "Who recorded the song \"King for a Day\"?", "answer": "Thompson Twins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b8d6aa2b42d4a3561a9f06", "question": "West Swan is a suburb in which Australian city?", "answer": "Perth", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af8f", "question": "What civil rights activist was born Malcolm Little?", "answer": "Malcolm X", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef96c96ce05a3942286ea1", "question": "Which martial art does Miss Piggy practice?", "answer": "Karate", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaeb", "question": "Which city is the capital of Tuscany?", "answer": "Florence", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9b2", "question": "What reaction takes place when food browns during cooking?", "answer": "Maillard Reaction\u00a0", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff0b78de662d71a53651013", "question": "Alan Frew, author of 2007's \"The Action Sandwich\", was also lead singer for which 80's pop group?", "answer": "Glass Tiger", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba87", "question": "In 1967, who became the first professional quarterback to pass for over 4,000 yards in a season?", "answer": "Joe Namath", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e4ccfe83fe1f2a824bb7", "question": "Where did the Franks settle after defeating the Romans?", "answer": "Gaul", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b599", "question": "Which artist's song was the 10 billionth iTunes download?", "answer": "Johnny Cash", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff25a4331a458464a93c46f", "question": "What is the process called by which people set out to amass large amounts of in-game currency to sell in the real world?", "answer": "Gold farming", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bae8", "question": "Twin brothers Ross and Norris McWhirter are best known for creating what reference book?", "answer": "Guinness Book of World Records", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59049ae8cf93664eb104869b", "question": "Marvel Comics was acquired by which major media and entertainment company in 2009?", "answer": "The Walt Disney Company", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c82", "question": "What year did Sting release his first solo album after leaving The Police?", "answer": "1985", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393f2", "question": "Who sang the title song for the 1978 suspense film \"Eyes of Laura Mars\"?", "answer": "Barbra Streisand", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b686", "question": "Figure skater Elvis Stojko comes from which country?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff6686852a821ff76ae8b04", "question": "Who are the first people known to have consumed chocolate?", "answer": "There is evidence that the ancient Olmecs of what is now Mexico consumed chocolate beverages as far back as 1900 BC.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c921", "question": "What is a group of Sparrows called?", "answer": "Host", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b673", "question": "What term was coined in 1983 to market the \"Gavilan SC\" portable computer?", "answer": "Laptop", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae60", "question": "What do the 36 columns surrounding the Lincoln Memorial represent?", "answer": "The number of states at the time of Lincoln's death", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398eb", "question": "What was the first name of Frasier\u2019s father on the sitcom \u201cFrasier\u201d?", "answer": "Martin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b283", "question": "What billionaire piloted the first hot-air balloon ever to cross the Atlantic?", "answer": "Richard Branson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c045", "question": "What's the triangular Asian pastry containing spiced meat?", "answer": "Samosa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fffa6bf73838c5c8a417f32", "question": "When held to ultraviolet light, what animal\u2019s urine glows in the dark?", "answer": "Cat", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9b2", "question": "What team did Vince Lombardi coach to two Super Bowl victories?", "answer": "Green Bay Packers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b52c", "question": "What postal code has Canada Post assigned to Santa Claus?", "answer": "H0H 0H0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5902a089cad1ec93f27df76d", "question": "What color is pure caffeine?", "answer": "White", "category": "Science"}, {"id": "6015e563fe83fe1f2a824bbc", "question": "The Islamic calendar is based on which cycle?", "answer": "Lunar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133984e", "question": "What is the name of the villain from the movie \"Mulan\"?", "answer": "Shan Yu", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1d9", "question": "What is Merlin's owl name in Disney's film \"The Sword in the Stone\"?", "answer": "Archimedes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2ff", "question": "Who did Pat Morita play on the ABC sitcom \"Happy Days\"?", "answer": "Arnold", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8ec", "question": "What is the study of production of materials at low temperatures called?", "answer": "Cryogenics", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a01", "question": "What is the name of Austin Powers' boss?", "answer": "Basil Exposition", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1d5", "question": "Philip Guichet is credited with inventing which popular cocktail?", "answer": "The Grasshopper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4d9a0708b8581f80b092b9", "question": "Which Bond actor passed away on May 23, 2017?", "answer": "Roger Moore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390b8", "question": "What is Dr. Zhivago's first name?", "answer": "Yuri", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b3234fbbf195a31e15d73aa", "question": "Which artist starred in the title role of the film \"Merry Christmas, Mr. Lawrence\"?", "answer": "David Bowie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5cd40b2e685cf15b733e9888", "question": "What South American country's name comes from the Latin word for silver?", "answer": "Argentina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fbe", "question": "In Greek literature, Chronos is the personification of what?", "answer": "Time", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133993c", "question": "What famous musician married his third wife, Nancy Shevell, in London in 2011?", "answer": "Paul McCartney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcbf", "question": "What model was married to musician Tommy Lee?", "answer": "Pamela Anderson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aa9", "question": "Who wrote The Angel Doll: A Christmas Story in 1996?", "answer": "Jerry Bledsoe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60062a82c9d816e292245c19", "question": "What artist created a 43 ft sculpture of a West Highland White Terrier puppy?", "answer": "Jeff Koons (He was commissioned to create the piece for Arolsen Castle in Germany.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5989abd6cb8751d53e7d7607", "question": "What is the \"nogada\" in the Mexican dish \"Chiles en nogada\"?", "answer": "Walnut based cream sauce", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339459", "question": "Who directed the 2001 movie \"Blow\"?", "answer": "Ted Demme", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e41", "question": "What 1964 Broadway hit centered on a milkman and his five daughters?", "answer": "Fiddler on the Roof", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe52f571bf59ab7d2e38114", "question": "What ingredient turns a martini into a dirty martini?", "answer": "Olive juice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e802d7de59ea584496fe99", "question": "In the TV show \"Sabrina the Teenage Witch\", what was the name of Sabrina's cat?", "answer": "Salem", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e147ef76ca6dac04a20ca52", "question": "Who was the first woman to fly solo across the Atlantic Ocean?", "answer": "Amelia Earhart", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c6b", "question": "The 1977 movie \"Saturday Night Fever\" was based on what \"New York\" magazine article?", "answer": "Tribal Rites of the New Saturday Night", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4eb", "question": "Which US state's name begins but doesn't end with the letter A?", "answer": "Arkansas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4a2", "question": "In which city could you find Bondi beach?", "answer": "Sydney", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b60f", "question": "What game comes packaged with a small plastic hourglass and sixteen different letter cubes?", "answer": "Boggle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59675fea2b59efe0e9417e9b", "question": "What ball has 32 panels?", "answer": "A soccer ball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133901c", "question": "Illustrator Sidney Paget created the trademarks of whom?", "answer": "Sherlock Holmes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5e90ff8ed7247dfc0fa0030b", "question": "What year was \"Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone\" published?", "answer": "1997", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4fe", "question": "What is the first foreign country you would reach if you go south of Detroit, Michigan?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f47", "question": "What is the real first name of Tyler Perry's famous character, Madea?", "answer": "Mabe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e147a6b6ca6dac04a20ca4e", "question": "When did Thomas Jefferson purchase the territory of Louisiana?", "answer": "1803", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a034", "question": "In the show \"Family Guy\", which US president has been seen happily singing in public about being nude?", "answer": "Bill Clinton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c73e", "question": "What part of the licorice plant gives the candy its distinctive flavor?", "answer": "The root", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b65d", "question": "A \"beaver\" was an attachment to what piece of human armor?", "answer": "Helmet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff3ce634f032c0db195b48d", "question": "What empire began as an alliance of three city-states?", "answer": "The\u00a0Aztec Empire, or the Triple Alliance, began as an alliance of three Nahua \"altepetl\" city-states.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3bd", "question": "What bird lays the smallest egg in relation to its size?", "answer": "Ostrich", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395d0", "question": "In The Simpsons, what is the name of Patty and Selma's iguana?", "answer": "Jub-Jub", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3867c73aa70ea0b70ad0", "question": "Which US state gets its name from a made-up word?", "answer": " Idaho (Mining lobbyist George M. Willing told Congress \"Idaho\" was a Native American phrase for \"gem of the mountains\". He made it up.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b05d", "question": "Which constitutional amendment gives US citizens the right to bear arms?", "answer": "Second", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab8e", "question": "What country shares a border with Cambodia to the northeast?", "answer": "Laos", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d27", "question": "What sport is the focus of the movie \"Cool Runnings\"?", "answer": "Bobsled", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5b6", "question": "What hormone enables women to have a sense of smell superior to men?", "answer": "Estrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59e3f6a85cb9e8bda682136d", "question": "What year did the first commercially produced tea bags appear on the market?", "answer": "1904", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a34f", "question": "What is the second largest country in the World?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339203", "question": "Who finds E.T.?", "answer": "Elliott", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c024", "question": "What is the fear of riding in vehicles known as?", "answer": "Ochophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be93", "question": "What company opened its first Italian eatery at Brooklyn's Kings Plaza Shopping Center in 1967?", "answer": "Sbarro", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0cc", "question": "What is the official name for the \"pound\" or \"number\" symbol on the telephone keypad?", "answer": "Octothorpe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cadf", "question": "For which viral disease did Louis Pasteur develop a vaccine?", "answer": "Rabies", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c193", "question": "Oil wrestling is the national sport of which country?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a16e", "question": "Who directed the 1988 film \"Mississippi Burning\"?", "answer": "Alan Parker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339330", "question": "What actor played the role of Captain John McIntyre on the TV show \"M*A*S*H\"?", "answer": "Wayne Rogers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2a8", "question": "What nation was led by Rameses the Great?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba81", "question": "On what part of your body would you wear mukluks?", "answer": "The feet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1ad", "question": "Who is Stevland Hardaway Morris better known as?", "answer": "Stevie Wonder", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecd0ecec223966ae8f88bc", "question": "Who is the flame-shooting guitarist in \"Mad Max: Fury Road\"?", "answer": "Sean Hape", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abe6", "question": "What country borders Guatemala to the north?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60136f6c1381754895396376", "question": "Where is Superman\u2019s Fortress of Solitude?", "answer": "Arctic Circle -- Although he's had different bachelor pads, he classically heads to the Arctic Circle when he wants to be alone.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3b8", "question": "What nation did Afghanistan belong to until 1919?", "answer": "United Kingdom", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9b1", "question": "Including the end zones, how long is an NFL regulation football field?", "answer": "120 yards", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8f0", "question": "What position did football hall-of-famer Joe Montana play?", "answer": "Quarterback", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ad7eba2b24f84e0b9f9ffdf", "question": "What town's name means \"House of Bread\" in Hebrew?", "answer": "Bethlehem", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff214f631a458464a93c45a", "question": "What is the name of the US President's official guest house?", "answer": "Blair House", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca5a", "question": "Like the majority of reptiles and fish, monotremes are mammals that do what?", "answer": "Lay eggs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b85", "question": "What\u2019s the ballet term for a 360 degree turn on one foot?", "answer": "A Pirouette", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b77d", "question": "What teacher taught Helen Keller the manual alphabet and Braille?", "answer": "Anne Sullivan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8de", "question": "Which Scandinavian nation has a yellow cross on its flag?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b564", "question": "What does the McDonalds in New Delhi make their burgers with?", "answer": "Mutton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c67e", "question": "What type of chemical bonding occurs between hydrogen and chlorine?", "answer": "Covalent", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cb6", "question": "In the nursery rhyme \"The Cat and the Fiddle\", what runs away with the spoon?", "answer": "The dish", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe738b8eec85e375820b266", "question": "Which African country was formerly known as Abyssinia?", "answer": "Ethiopia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5af985ccaeb0982ee455954f", "question": "Who created the \"Fantasic Four\" superhero team?", "answer": "Stan Lee and Jack Kirby", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600f7505a9e54d890926f702", "question": "What is illegal to eat with a cherry pie in Kansas?", "answer": "Ice cream", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe93a0f6bd93ce3a4e5f693", "question": "Who was the first scientist to observe live cells?", "answer": "Antonie van Leeuwenhoek", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a4a952561d1b4d384d5d675", "question": "What are \"Castanets\"?", "answer": "A type of musical instrument", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba9b", "question": "What chapel do Cardinals congregate in to elect a new Pope?", "answer": "Sistine Chapel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a83", "question": "Which original \"Star Trek\" character was played by James Doohan?", "answer": "Scotty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0ff", "question": "Lucille Fay LeSueur became famous as who?", "answer": "Joan Crawford", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b77b", "question": "What 1990's fad involved something known as a slammer?", "answer": "Pogs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe937c36bd93ce3a4e5f676", "question": "Gamophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Marriage and commitment", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133977f", "question": "What Canadian actor starred in Airplane! as Dr. Shirley Rumack?", "answer": "Leslie Neilson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399e8", "question": "In the movie \"Raising Arizona\", what brand of diapers does Nicolas Cage steal from the convenience store?", "answer": "Huggies", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a24b", "question": "What is the name of Bryan Adams' third studio album, released in 1983?", "answer": "Cuts Like a Knife", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c348", "question": "Who is considered the father of the computer due to his plans for a steam-powered difference engine?", "answer": "Charles Babbage", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0be", "question": "In the traditional song, what did the children dance around \"on a cold and frosty morning\"?", "answer": "The mulberry bush", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd18bf729d03ab85b632b32", "question": "Who played the role of Gunnery Sergeant Hartman in the film \"Full Metal Jacket\"?", "answer": "R. Lee Ermy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339855", "question": "Totoro from the movie \"My Neighbor Totoro\" lives in what kind of tree?", "answer": "Camphor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a10b20565ad31a57c79f", "question": "Which country created the official marathon length of 26.2 miles?", "answer": "United Kingdom", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339156", "question": "Who said: \"We are more popular than Jesus\"?", "answer": "John Lennon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef63736ce05a3942286e64", "question": "Who was the first woman to host an American late night show?", "answer": "Joan Rivers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2cf", "question": "Who played the role of Julia Brougham in the 1947 film \"The Bishop's Wife\"?", "answer": "Loretta Young", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c520fbde8045e48466a7", "question": "The scientific name for narwhal translates to what?", "answer": "\"One tooth, one horn\" -- It is Latin for Monodon monoceros. Interesting, the whale also make a sound best described as purring.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b323158bf195a31e15d7383", "question": "Which British playwright wrote the screenplay for the 1981 film \"The French Lieutenant's Woman\"?", "answer": "Harold Pinter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa08", "question": "Budapest is the capital of which European country?", "answer": "Hungary", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "594a64ca2ebb971c1417fba8", "question": "Who was the first US actress to be featured on a US postage stamp?", "answer": "Grace Kelly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399a6", "question": "What popular radio DJ was the original voice of Shaggy on \"Scooby-Doo\"?", "answer": "Casey Kasem", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594d07ba1a1c922dd1ac64bb", "question": "Who was the Greek god of sleep?", "answer": "Hypnos", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c06f", "question": "Tin or aluminum is the traditional gift for which anniversary?", "answer": "Tenth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58f16745f7c52aae91cc07b7", "question": "In which continent would you find the Republic of Guinea-Bissau?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b485", "question": "What was the Republic of Nauru previously known as?", "answer": "Pleasant Island", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a94d", "question": "What two \"Great\" lakes are the largest two lakes entirely within Canada?", "answer": "Great Bear and Great Slave lakes", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b505", "question": "What two skills make up the winter biathlon?", "answer": "Cross-country skiing and target shooting", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa40d5c73aa70ea0b70b0a", "question": "Where is the first underwater art museum in the U.S.?", "answer": "Santa Rosa Beach, Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b99e", "question": "What does the abbreviation DOS stand for in the operating system MS-DOS?", "answer": "Disk Operating System", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bbd", "question": "What popular designer was responsible for the wardrobe of \"The Fifth Element\"?", "answer": "Jean Paul Gaultier", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b240", "question": "What royal subject married Lisa Halaby?", "answer": "King Hussein of Jordan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600cc4416de0eb824d4052f1", "question": "What country's Indigenous name translates to \"Land of the Long White Cloud\"?", "answer": "New Zealand -- In the 1200s, Maori settlers called the North Island \"Aotearoa\", which translates to \"long white cloud\".", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6014c50efbde8045e48466a6", "question": "What is a phanerogam?", "answer": "Plants that produce seeds -- The most advanced plants on the evolutionary scale, they used to go by the name spermatophytes.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6ec", "question": "The cerebrum is the largest part of what organ?", "answer": "The brain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febd4bc7e83c707845b215f", "question": "During which period in Japanese history did \"Seven Samurai\" take place?", "answer": "Sengoku Period", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5eb734555e259d7869087328", "question": "Which US president went on record saying that he wished he could\u2019ve hanged his vice president during his administration?", "answer": "Andrew Jackson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ea4", "question": "Farnsworth Bentley became famous for holding whose umbrellas?", "answer": "Puff Daddy's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b208", "question": "Who fretted over exponential population growth in his \"An Essay on the Principles of Population\"?", "answer": "Thomas Malthus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a47a", "question": "In which country is the Simpson Desert located?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339108", "question": "Who wrote the book \"Man's Search for Meaning\"?", "answer": "Viktor E. Frankl", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7dd", "question": "What Asian dog breed is notable for its blue or black tongue?", "answer": "The Chow Chow", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015fcbffe83fe1f2a824c44", "question": "The founder of Atari also founded which pizza restaurant?", "answer": "Chuck E. Cheese", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b984", "question": "Which small guitar associated with George Formby was patented in Hawaii in 1917?", "answer": "Ukulele", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b08", "question": "In which country do Stieg Larsson's Millennium Trilogy novels take place?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59a5527e3e1c6f9840ba3196", "question": "The telephone country code 82 would connect you with which country?", "answer": "South Korea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6002436e4be4723ccac22196", "question": "In Jonathan Swift\u2019s \"Gulliver\u2019s Travels\", what is the name of the island inhabited by tiny people?", "answer": "Lilliput", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd6a1826c0f9723ab15cb3a", "question": "Who was the first honorary citizen of the U.S.?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9b7", "question": "What name is given to twins who are joined together by some part of their anatomy?", "answer": "Siamese", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c79e", "question": "How many moons does the planet Neptune have?", "answer": "14", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6ad", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Granite State\"?", "answer": "New Hampshire", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe93b546bd93ce3a4e5f6a2", "question": "What is the study of water called?", "answer": "Hydrology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad04", "question": "What is a four letter Gaelic name for Scotland?", "answer": "Alba", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600cc1e76de0eb824d4052e3", "question": "What islands make up the British Virgin Islands?", "answer": "The British Virgin Islands is a former colony that includes the islands of Virgin Gorda, Tortola, Anegada, and Jost Van Dyke.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eae", "question": "Who won Pulitzers for his plays \"A Delicate Balance\", \"Seascape\", and \"Three Tall Women\"?", "answer": "Edward Albee", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7c1", "question": "In pool, what color is the 5-ball?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a376", "question": "What is the capital of Sweden?", "answer": "Stockholm", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133922b", "question": "What is the general subject of the books sold by Hugh Grant's character in the movie \"Notting Hill\"?", "answer": "Travel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c90cf5552800b05cac20f09", "question": "What US state is nicknamed \"Little Rhody\"?", "answer": "Rhode Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3cc", "question": "Due to getting sick, which astronaut was replaced in the Apollo XIII mission?", "answer": "Ken Mattingly", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388cd", "question": "One of Oscar Wilde's best-known works is a play titled \"The Importance of Being ...\"what?", "answer": "Earnest", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fbb", "question": "Who is the author of the novel \"Jude the Obscure\"?", "answer": "Thomas Hardy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8bc", "question": "How many cards are usually used in a game of solitaire?", "answer": "52", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea364aff048f679a45ab0b", "question": "Carrots are a good source of which vitamin?", "answer": "A", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ba", "question": "In the movie industry, what does a Gaffer do?", "answer": "Design and execution of lighting", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594d070d1a1c922dd1ac64b4", "question": "Which town do Fred, Wilma, Barney, and Betty live in?", "answer": "Bedrock", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd9662e23c87fd04dd15e01", "question": "What year was the first computer mouse prototype built?", "answer": "1964", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b21", "question": "Stings first solo album was entitled \"The Dream of the Blue...\" what?", "answer": "Turtles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecdd0dec223966ae8f88fd", "question": "Which Yankee was nicknamed \"The Iron Horse\"?", "answer": "Lou Gehrig", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60173d2b44491cbd7c5a17aa", "question": "What is the oldest active international airline?", "answer": "KLM Royal Dutch Airlines -- Founded in 1919, KLM is also the\u00a0oldest airline in the world\u00a0still operating under its original name.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8af6101dd7bf43be5e789", "question": "What do phillumenists collect?", "answer": "Matchboxes and match-related items", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c3e97a9ebfabb9c85d8a965", "question": "Which popular beverage's name is German for \"storeroom\"?", "answer": "Lager", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef5c716ce05a3942286e20", "question": "Which actress keeps her Oscar in her bathroom so guests can hold it and make speeches in the mirror shame-free?", "answer": "Kate Winslet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8d0", "question": "Sound Navigation Ranging is better known as what?", "answer": "Sonar", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe65d811f3c0ead6880d61c", "question": "In ancient times, what were professional writers called?", "answer": "Scribes", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ab972886faa38a764be527", "question": "Which car manufacturer was the first to include seat belts as a standard feature in their vehicles?", "answer": "Saab", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60121c2b63c99d48cd169b12", "question": "Norman Rockwell painted 323 covers for which magazine?", "answer": "\"Saturday Evening Post\" -- The magazine featured Rockwell\u2019s work from 1916 to 1963.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2d9", "question": "What military legend was nicknamed \"Gentleman Johnny\"?", "answer": "John Burgoyne", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff6685052a821ff76ae8b03", "question": "Around what sea did Jesus call His first apostles?", "answer": "Christ first saw Peter and Andrew close to the Sea of Galilee. He beseeched them to follow Him.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abbd", "question": "Where might you drink Retsina wine?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398c7", "question": "What ragtime musician first performed \"The Entertainer\" in 1902?", "answer": "Scott Joplin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b988", "question": "By what name is Mardi Gras known in Britain?", "answer": "Shrove Tuesday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "597cd487e347d002c297e4b0", "question": "Which famous English actor was charged with lewd conduct in 1995?", "answer": "Hugh Grant", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c489", "question": "What is the term for the visible surface of the Sun?", "answer": "Photosphere", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a899d9d60d398dc9cf7a6ad", "question": "What US Secretary of State received the Nobel Peace Prize in 1973?", "answer": "Henry Kissinger", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b7ff9623a3a814d89068c54", "question": "\"Amharic\" is the official language of which African country?", "answer": "Ethiopia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b4c0e49076251badbeacc", "question": "Who got married in the very first White House wedding?", "answer": "Dolley Madison\u2019s sister -- Lucy Payne Washington, the sister of First Lady Dolley Madison, married Thomas Todd in 1819.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b1", "question": "Who played the female lead role in the 2007 movie \"Stardust\"?", "answer": "Claire Danes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be18", "question": "Which modern instrument was called the sackbut until the nineteenth century?", "answer": "The trombone", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1c8", "question": "In 1980, what executed man was added to the Anglican Church's calendar of saint?", "answer": "Sir Thomas More", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a42e", "question": "Which ocean is between South America and Africa?", "answer": "Atlantic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b97a", "question": "The French Tennis Open is played at which venue?", "answer": "Roland Garros", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ace", "question": "Who played Leon, Roseanne's boss at the caf\u00e9, on the sitcom \"Roseanne\"?", "answer": "Martin Mull", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594d06931a1c922dd1ac64ad", "question": "Who devised a method for classifying fingerprints?", "answer": "Francis Galton", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd96e9e23c87fd04dd15e3a", "question": "As of 2020, who was the last human to walk on the moon?", "answer": "Eugene Cernan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6a9e020565ad31a57c80c", "question": "Whose image is on the U.S. half-dollar from 1916 to 1947?", "answer": "Lady Liberty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3b6", "question": "Which was the first Space-ready Shuttle to be launched?", "answer": "Columbia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fde519ec6c6b019850c9a90", "question": "Herbert Hoover became well known when he organized relief efforts for what country after World War I?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c11d", "question": "What word is used for an adult female sheep?", "answer": "Ewe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cafe", "question": "What popular drug was once extracted from the bark of the cinchona tree?", "answer": "Quinine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcbe", "question": "What model was married to musician Marilyn Manson?", "answer": "Dita Von Teese", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600245024be4723ccac221ab", "question": "In Leonardo da Vinci's Annunciation, who is depicted with the virgin Mary?", "answer": "Gabriel -- The angel is sent by God to tell the virgin Mary that she will miraculously conceive and give birth to a son, Jesus.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c06d", "question": "In what decade was Montreal Canadien great Maurice \"Rocket\" Richard born?", "answer": "1920s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fc85551abc30a8194e188ac", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"The Deep\"?", "answer": "Peter Benchley", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe36e5c0ada16518afdc044", "question": "What temperature should you not exceed when melting chocolate?", "answer": "120 F or 49 C", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c4b5fbde8045e48466a0", "question": "What does the African dung beetle use to navigate at night?", "answer": "The Milky Way -- The only animal known to navigate using the Milky Way, they can move objects that are 50 times their weight.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b38b", "question": "Who became UK's Prime Minister following the assassination of Spencer Perceval in 1812?", "answer": "Robert Banks Jenkinson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fde493ac6c6b019850c9a6d", "question": "Which Old Testament prophet said \"Thou art the man\"?", "answer": "Nathan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c31d", "question": "What is added to bread to make it swell?", "answer": "Yeast", "category": "science"}, {"id": "596dfdb79616e6c6d4eba4f8", "question": "On the hit show \"Seinfeld\" what was Kramer's first name? ", "answer": "Cosmo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f16ae3f7c52aae91cc07e2", "question": "What sort of food are \"rollmops\"?", "answer": "Fish", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a30e", "question": "Which character did Evan Handler play on the TV show \"Californication\"?", "answer": "Charlie Runkle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5989a972cb8751d53e7d7600", "question": "The State of Washington was originally going to be called what?", "answer": "Columbia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a4a954861d1b4d384d5d677", "question": "What is pumpernickel?", "answer": "A type of German bread", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae28", "question": "In which decade was the Panama Canal completed?", "answer": "1910s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339268", "question": "What movie did Michael J. Fox learn to skateboard for?", "answer": "Back to the Future", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393ef", "question": "What actor was the executive producer of the mystery series \"Push, Nevada\"?", "answer": "Ben Affleck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c648", "question": "What is the name of Pluto's largest satellite?", "answer": "Charon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390de", "question": "What is the name of the leading female singer in an opera?", "answer": "Prima donna", "category": "arts"}]